James Wirth

Greensboro, NC | (704) 728-1907 | Email | LinkedIn | GitHub

IT Support Representative

US Army Veteran with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. 5+ years of professional experience in the military; gained a comprehensive knowledge of leadership, strategic planning, and resource allocation. Recent graduate of ACI Learning's Advanced IT Infrastructure Support Program. Extensively trained in networking, hardware, software, Active Directory, ticketing systems, and end user support.

Areas of Expertise

- Customer Service
- Technical Support
- Active Directory
- Configuring Software
- Help Desk & Ticketing
- Windows 10 & Office
- End User Support
- Network Management
- Operating Systems
- Analytical Skills

- Prioritization
- Software & Hardware
- TCP/IP Troubleshooting
- LAN/WAN/VLAN/Wi-Fi
- Data Management

Languages: Java, C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL **Foundational Concepts:** Agile-Scrum framework, Git

Education & Certifications

Computer User Support Specialist Program | ACI Learning | Denver, CO

2021 Graduate

✓ Professional Certifications (In Progress): ITIL v4 | CompTIA A+ | Network+ | Security+

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

2021 Graduate

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Concentration: Cyber Security

Professional Experience

<u>Logistics Specialist</u> | Army Reserves | Various Locations

October 2015 - Present

- Communicated priorities and job tasks to hundreds of staff members on various shifts.
- Conducted periodic machine inspections and routine tests on 30 915A3 Tractor-Trailer Systems to ensure that operation standards were met.
- Supervised and operated wheeled vehicles (M1083A1 / 915A3) over all types of terrain to safely transport cargo, troops, and provided advanced mobility on all missions.

Instructor | Mathnasium | Huntersville, NC

May 2020 - July 2021

- Improved average students' test scores to highest percentiles.
- Approached different learning styles to help students retain difficult concepts.
- Helped students be more confident in themselves towards their work and others.

Assistant Manager | Urban Air | Cornelius, NC

December 2019 - January 2021

- Sorted logistics of up to 200 customers within time constraints to yield the most activities.
- Operated and troubleshoot machinery that the kids used to safely participate.
- Enforced corporate rules and standards to avoid injuries while maintaining an energetic atmosphere.
- Trained 17 employees to perform their job jobs efficiently and with minimal errors

Projects:

- Implemented personal budget app where users can view monthly budgets.
- Designed user interface for "Send-a-Card" to send loved one's virtual cards.
- Produced "Crop Market" app for farmers to trade good to those who can provide services.
- Created note-taking app for students to use online.